First, draw three inner lines to be folded, then select these inner lines that are slightly wider and cut them.
After cutting, you can select these panels separately. We will use the function of shrink and fold the panels more simply and steadily.
The reason why we choose to cut and not cut and sew is to prevent the sewing line between the panel and the panel to be affected by the fire.
First, make the panel on the top. This panel is the panel on the outside of the fold.
After the fire, create the sewing line.
Then use the folding arrangement tool to fold the sleeve panel.
Then print the clothing panel.
The printed panel will be harder due to the properties.
It will be easier to use the folding arrangement tool.
The folding arrangement tool is used to reduce the angle of the sleeve and prevent the fold.
The top clothing panel is frozen.
Use the 120% of the bending force for the first panel.
When the force is over 100%, the width of the panel will be wider and the effect will be slightly increased due to hardening.
After freezing the panel, activate the second panel and sew it to the first layer.
Do the same on the other side to increase the shrinkage and hardening
Since the inner layer is sewn directly to the inner layer, it does not need to be frozen
Then activate the inner layer and sew it to the second layer
Then add it to the outside and add it to the inside
After finishing, start to simulate
After the simulation is stable, remove all panels and change the shrinkage rate to 100 and then simulate
After the simulation is stable, remove the hardening and simulate
After the simulation is stable, please hide the outer panel to check if there is a fold in it or not
After the simulation is stable, please hide the inner panel to check if there is a fold in it or not
After the simulation is stable, reduce the size of the
And then merge the panels
Due to the characteristic of the triangular mesh, it will cause the fold to be made
At this time, select the right button to pop up the reset grid in the menu, and you can re-arrange the grid distribution to make the fold position smoother.
After folding one side of the sleeve, you can delete the other side of the sleeve and then directly press Ctrl plus D to align to the other side.
Adjust the position of the fold position in the 3D window and simulate the stability.